Sintayehu Mekonnen

Clarkston, GA

sintemite@gmail.com ~ Cell: (404) 935-2192

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Dedicated to providing the best customer service possible. Excellent communication skills, able to multi-task in a fast-paced environment and meet deadlines. Experience in leadership roles and making decisions. Outstanding and conscientious team player. Willing to learn new skills and open for advanced opportunities. Possess a positive attitude and experience in diverse environments. Skilled in basics of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Microsoft Office 365, internet and email. Bilingual in English and Amharic.

EDUCATION

Georgia Piedmont Technical College, Clarkston, GA

Computer Support Specialist Degree 2016 - present

RELATED WORK SKILLS

Computer Skills

- Skills and knowledge of Web Technology (File format, Domain Registration, source code, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Advanced computer skills for Google Chrome Password Generator and Password Manager.
- Knowledge on Coding Tools (Atom source code editor, Browser, Chrome Inspector, GitHub repository creation, Cyber Duck, and Web Hosting).
- Basic skills for window operating system including Office 365.
- Computer hardware and software applications.
- Computer Networking Fundamentals.
- Install, configure software, and setup printers, scanners, and other peripherals.
- Enters customer and account data by inputting alphabetic and numeric information
- Security Fundamentals, Internet, Email, and virus protection.
- Read technical manuals or conduct computer diagnostics to investigate and resolve problems.
- Install and perform minor repairs to hardware, software, or peripheral equipment, following design or installation specifications.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Dekalb Farmers Market – Decatur, GA Cashier/Customer Service Rep 07/2015 – 01/2017

- Received payments for merchandise by cash, credit cards, check, or automatic debits.
- Issued receipts, refunds, credits, or change due to customers.
- Counted money in cash drawers at the beginning of shifts to ensure that amounts are correct
- Greeted customers entering establishments and help them make their selection
- Maintained clean and orderly checkout areas
- Answered customers' questions and provide information on procedures or policies
- Calculate total payments received during a time and reconcile this with total sales
- Processed merchandise returns and exchanges

Communication Affairs – Addis Ababa, Ethiopia Regional Relation Expert 07/2012 – 03/2015

- Document customers' information in the computer
- Attached and sent file to institution
- Assisted in the development of plans and report formation
- Analyzed and evaluate the function of agencies and organizations and their impact on international relations

Gurage Zone Education Office – Wolkite, Ethiopia <u>Coordinator</u> 04/2008 – 03/2011

- Organized and facilitated training for administrators, supervisors and teachers
- Selected trainers for program and made schedules for training
- Provided support to the school by helping to implement the curriculum
- Organized and collected teacher's data to evaluate activities and overall progress

CERTIFICATION/TRAINING

- Certificate in Microsoft Office application including Office 365 (April 2011)
- Certificate in Web Developer Bootcamp (March 2018)
- Certificate in Transformational Leadership Development and Decision-Making (December 2012)